<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dale Richardson</title>
    <link>/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dale Richardson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Learned From My First R Conference (useR!2017)</title>
      <link>/blog/what-i-learned-from-my-first-r-conference-user-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/what-i-learned-from-my-first-r-conference-user-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-learned-from-my-first-user-conference&#34;&gt;What I learned from my first useR! conference&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been exactly one week since the ending of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.user2017.brussels&#34;&gt;useR!2017 conference&lt;/a&gt; in Brussels, Belgium. I have to say that I am so happy that I decided to go to the conference. To put it succintly, it was the best conference I have ever attended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;blog/IMG_1891.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, I was a bit hesitant to even register for the conference. I thought to myself, &amp;ldquo;Man, you haven&amp;rsquo;t been using R for that long. You&amp;rsquo;re going to stick out like a sore thumb. Everyone knows more than you!&amp;rdquo; This thought was quickly followed by several others all along the lines of convincing myself that I&amp;rsquo;m an &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Impostor_syndrome&#34;&gt;imposter&lt;/a&gt;. Thankfully, I got over these self-defeating sentiments and registered for the conference, paying out of my own pocket. This conference was too big of an opportunity to miss and boy am I glad I went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the key take-aways for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;r-is-much-more-than-a-programming-language-it-is-also-a-community&#34;&gt;R is much more than a programming language: it is also a community&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tucked away in my office at work or at home, I often feel isolated in my quest to become a data scientist. I haven&amp;rsquo;t met personally with any local R users, not even at my own institute (though I hope to change this in the near future!). Typically my enthusiasm for R is celebrated in isolation, usually when learning something new through an online course, book or youtube video. So it was quite a shock to arrive at the conference venue and encounter roughly a thousand other R users!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from the initial overwhelm of taking in the sheer number of attendees, was the very friendly and welcoming attitude that generally permeated the conference. People were genuinely happy to be there and happy to discuss all things R and not R. To me, it felt like the community was very inclusive and non-judgemental &amp;ndash; in general very respectful and welcoming of people from all walks of life and experience levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-got-to-meet-cool-people&#34;&gt;I got to meet cool people&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the major highlights of my useR!2017 experience was getting to meet a lot of different people: statisticians, data scientists, economists, teachers and even an old colleague. An ad hoc &lt;code&gt;DrinkeR&lt;/code&gt; whatsapp group was even formed so that good beer could be drunk in good company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;useR!2017 granted me the opportunity to personally speak with &amp;ldquo;actual data scientists&amp;rdquo;. Strangely enough, I had never met an industry data scientist prior to this conference, so I took every occasion to ask questions on what their path to data science looked like. I got some great encouragement and some information on what their interview processes were like. I have to admit, I was a little intimidated of some of things I read on the internet regarding the entire interview process of getting hired as a data scientist, but after talking with several people at the conference I realized that no one was perfectly ready, everyone was nervous and to just go for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another big highlight was getting to meet and chat with David Robinson, chief data scientist at Stack Overflow. Not only did he give a great presentation, he&amp;rsquo;s extremely gregarious and super open to giving advice and tips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;IMG_1881.png&#34; alt=&#34;David Robinson, myself and Thanos Gatos at the conference dinner.&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had some nice conversations about life in academia, the usefulness of data science bootcamps, work life balance and how to best manage your time to get the most out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;blog/tweet.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons I was inspired to go to this conference was that I recently took the Duke University Coursera specialization, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/specializations/statistics&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Statistics with R&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; and was just so impressed by the material and had a great experience in the course. When I saw that one of the lead instructors for this course, Dr. Mine Çetinkaya-Rundel was going to be a keynote speaker, I knew I had to register just for the off chance that I could meet her in person and thank her for doing such a wonderful job at teaching. Incidentally, I think she gave one of the best talks of the entire conference, which you can &lt;a href=&#34;https://channel9.msdn.com/Events/useR-international-R-User-conferences/useR-International-R-User-2017-Conference/KEYNOTE-Teaching-data-science-to-new-useRs&#34;&gt;watch here&lt;/a&gt;. Anyway, long story short - yes, I got to meet her and say thank you in person on the last day of the conference after the closing ceremony, which was super cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-saw-a-lot-of-interesting-talks&#34;&gt;I saw a lot of interesting talks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from the social aspects that I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned above, the breadth of topics covered at this conference was incredible. There were so many different threads and interests represented, all tied together through the common use of R. One of the drawbacks of having such a large conference is that almost all sessions ran in parallel, so you had to pick and choose what you wanted to see. Fortunately, all talks are now &lt;a href=&#34;https://channel9.msdn.com/Events/useR-international-R-User-conferences/useR-International-R-User-2017-Conference?sort=rating&amp;amp;direction=asc&#34;&gt;available online&lt;/a&gt; in HD video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the talks I enjoyed are (not limited to) the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://channel9.msdn.com/Events/useR-international-R-User-conferences/useR-International-R-User-2017-Conference/KEYNOTE-Teaching-data-science-to-new-useRs&#34;&gt;Teaching data science to new useRs - Mine Cetinkaya-Rundel (Duke University and RStudio, USA)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://channel9.msdn.com/Events/useR-international-R-User-conferences/useR-International-R-User-2017-Conference/Text-mining-the-tidy-way&#34;&gt;Text mining, the tidy way - Julia Silge (Data Scientist at Stack Overflow)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://channel9.msdn.com/Events/useR-international-R-User-conferences/useR-International-R-User-2017-Conference/KEYNOTE-Structural-Equation-Modeling-models-software-and-stories&#34;&gt;Structural Equation Modeling: models, software and stories - Yves Rosseel (Gent University, Belgium)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://channel9.msdn.com/Events/useR-international-R-User-conferences/useR-International-R-User-2017-Conference/Scraping-data-with-rvest-and-purrr&#34;&gt;Scraping data with rvest and purrr - Max Humber&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you missed the conference, have a look at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://user2017.brussels/schedule&#34;&gt;program&lt;/a&gt; and then go find the video on &lt;a href=&#34;https://channel9.msdn.com/Events/useR-international-R-User-conferences/useR-International-R-User-2017-Conference/&#34;&gt;channel9&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-discovered-that-users-have-a-hex-sticker-obsession&#34;&gt;I discovered that useRs have a hex sticker obsession&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess I was totally out of the loop, but prior to attending useR, I had no idea how obsessed people are with collecting hex stickers. Well, I have to say that I totally love it and jumped on the bandwagon. I plastered a few stickers on my machine in honor of the tidyverse and to show my support for online education platforms like &lt;a href=&#34;www.datacamp.com&#34;&gt;Datacamp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;blog/hex-stickers.png&#34; alt=&#34;Cool stickers from Rstudio&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;final-remarks&#34;&gt;Final remarks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thoroughly enjoyed my first useR event. What made the event so special for me was not just the quality of the content, but the quality of the community. There is a real sense of camaraderie shared amongst useRs. I look forward to the next event, &lt;a href=&#34;/registration/&#34;&gt;useR!2018 in Brisbane, Australia&lt;/a&gt;. I am not sure if I will be able to attend, but I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to visit Australia and this might be the purrfect reason to go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find yourself reading this and are unsure if going to a conference like useR! is right for you, I highly recommend taking the plunge and just going for it! You&amp;rsquo;ll meet wonderful people, learn tons of stuff and have a great time!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Dale</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;currently&#34;&gt;Currently&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a postdoc in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.igc.gulbenkian.pt/pduque&#34;&gt;Plant Molecular Biology Laboratory&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.igc.gulbenkian.pt&#34;&gt;Instituto Gulbenkian de Ciência (IGC)&lt;/a&gt;, a research institution located just outside of Lisbon, Portugal. I primarily rely on &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; and a suite of bioinformatics tools to analyze large-scale genomic changes in response to abiotic stress in the model plant organism, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arabidopsis_thaliana&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Arabidopsis thaliana&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, commonly known as the &amp;ldquo;thale cress&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-transition&#34;&gt;In transition&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I hold a special place in my heart for research science, it has become abundantly clear to me that I need to move into a new challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe it is important to be engaged in something that one truly loves doing, where motivation arises without force and passion drives you effortlessly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In late 2016, I learned about the fields of &lt;code&gt;data anayltics&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;data science&lt;/code&gt; and quickly became intrigued and then impassioned. I started to listen to all sorts of data science podcasts, sign up for online courses, browse bootcamp options and just basically immerse myself in the subject as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quickly realized that this was not going to be an overnight endeavor but instead was going to be an extended, uphill journey fraught with challenges (internal and external).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I believe it is only by facing our challenges that we truly grow personally and professionally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so I find myself here, creating this space as a chronicle of my journey from research science to data science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&#34;ultimately-my-goal-is-to-shift-out-of-my-role-as-a-postdoc-and-pivot-to-a-role-as-a-data-analyst-scientist-in-early-2018&#34;&gt;Ultimately, my goal is to shift out of my role as a postdoc and pivot to a role as a data analyst/scientist in early 2018.&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions or suggestions, feel free to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/yogiwankinobi&#34;&gt;ask me on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;mailto: dalesan@gmail.com&#34;&gt;write me an email&lt;/a&gt;!.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum Vitae</title>
      <link>/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 14:31:31 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cv/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dale-richardson-phd&#34;&gt;Dale Richardson, PhD&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a bioinformatics analyst of large scale genomics data and aspiring data scientist with an intense dedication to continued learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;scientific-research-interests&#34;&gt;Scientific research interests&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Post-transcriptional gene regulation, alternative splicing, comparative genomics, abiotic stress response&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;currently&#34;&gt;Currently&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I conduct research on alternative splicing and abiotic stress responses in the model plant, &lt;em&gt;Arabidopsis thaliana&lt;/em&gt;. In my spare time, I take online courses in preparation for a career transition into data analysis/data science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current/Upcoming courses include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.edx.org/course/introduction-computer-science-mitx-6-00-1x-10&#34;&gt;Introduction to Computer Science and Programming Using Python (May 30, 2017, MITx)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.edx.org/course/analytics-edge-mitx-15-071x-3&#34;&gt;The Analytics Edge (June 6, 2017, MITx)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/learn/statistics-project&#34;&gt;Statistics with R Capstone (Starts on July 17, 2017, Duke University/Coursera)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;specialized-in&#34;&gt;Specialized in&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next Generation RNASeq data analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data analysis and statistics with R&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plant Molecular Biology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quantitative Real Time PCR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;would-like-to-be-specialized-in&#34;&gt;Would like to be specialized in&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python programming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SQL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Machine Learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;education&#34;&gt;Education&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2010&#34;&gt;2010&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ph.D. Evolutionary Genomics&lt;/strong&gt; [&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uni-koeln.de&#34;&gt;University of Cologne&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2006&#34;&gt;2006&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M.S. Botany&lt;/strong&gt; [&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.colostate.edu&#34;&gt;Colorado State University&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2004&#34;&gt;2004&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.S. Biology&lt;/strong&gt; [&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.colostate.edu&#34;&gt;Colorado State University&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;certificates&#34;&gt;Certificates&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2017&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction to Probability and Data by Duke University on Coursera&lt;/strong&gt; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/verify/X73W7V25QQ5D&#34;&gt;Coursera Certificate&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inferential Statistics Duke University on Coursera&lt;/strong&gt; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/S2R7J7ZDJZCU&#34;&gt;Coursera Certificate&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Linear Regression and Modeling Duke University on Coursera&lt;/strong&gt; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/F95LDH6EVEER&#34;&gt;Coursera Certificate&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bayesian Statistics Duke University on Coursera&lt;/strong&gt; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/verify/CGPEHRD8TA7L&#34;&gt;Coursera Certificate&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced Biostatistics Workshop&lt;/strong&gt; [&lt;a href=&#34;http://gtpb.igc.gulbenkian.pt/bicourses/ABSTAT17&#34;&gt;Gulbenkian Training Program in Bioinformatics&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Data Scientist’s Toolbox by  Johns Hopkins University on Coursera&lt;/strong&gt; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/verify/CPY3WDPJGYX5&#34;&gt;Coursera Certificate&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R Programming by Johns Hopkins University on Coursera&lt;/strong&gt; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/verify/65UEVZALXRTE&#34;&gt;Coursera Certificate&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting and Cleaning Data by Johns Hopkins University on Coursera&lt;/strong&gt; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/verify/D6DCU236WVRG&#34;&gt;Coursera Certificate&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reproducible Research by Johns Hopkins University on Coursera&lt;/strong&gt; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/verify/NHDLU8M6F45H&#34;&gt;Coursera Certificate&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exploratory Data Analysis by Johns Hopkins University on Coursera&lt;/strong&gt; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/verify/DFL54DDED8QP&#34;&gt;Coursera Certificate&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Precision Medicine Workshop&lt;/strong&gt; [&lt;a href=&#34;http://gtpb.igc.gulbenkian.pt/bicourses/index.html&#34;&gt;Gulbenkian Training Program in Bioinformatics&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;awards&#34;&gt;Awards&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2012&#34;&gt;2012&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post-Doctoral Fellowship, &lt;em&gt;FCT&lt;/em&gt;, Lisbon, Portugal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2007&#34;&gt;2007&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Travel Fellowship, &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Systems for Molecular Biology&lt;/em&gt;, Vienna, Austria&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2006-1&#34;&gt;2006&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PhD Fellowship, &lt;em&gt;International Graduate School for Genetics and Functional Genomics&lt;/em&gt;, Cologne, Germany&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2003&#34;&gt;2003&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NSF Research Experiences for Undergraduates, &lt;em&gt;National Science Foundation&lt;/em&gt;, Arlington, Virginia, USA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;publications&#34;&gt;Publications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;journals&#34;&gt;Journals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2017-1&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carvalho, S.D.*, &lt;strong&gt;Richardson, D.N*&lt;/strong&gt;., Cruz, T.M.D., Carvalho, R.F., Barbosa, I.C.R., Stecca, K.L., Kinney, A.J., Zeidler, M., Duque, P. The plant-specific SCL30a SR protein confers ABA-Dependent salt and osmotic stress tolerance during seed germination in Arabidopsis. Under submission. * co-authors&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ling Y, Alshareef S, Butt H, Lozano-Juste J, Li L, Galal AA, Moustafa A, Momin AA, Tashkandi M, &lt;strong&gt;Richardson DN&lt;/strong&gt;, Fujii H, Arold S, Rodriguez PL, Duque P, Mahfouz MM. (2017) Pre-mRNA splicing repression triggers abiotic stress signaling in plants. The Plant Journal 89, 291-309. &lt;em&gt;5-YR IF: 6.468, Citations: 2; Top 2% in Plant Science&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2014&#34;&gt;2014&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cruz, T.M.D., Carvalho, R.F., &lt;strong&gt;Richardson, D.N.&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;amp; Duque, P. (2014) Abscisic acid (ABA) regulation of Arabidopsis SR protein gene expression. International Journal of Molecular Sciences 15(10): 17541-17564. &lt;em&gt;5-YR IF: 3.213 Citations: 11; Q2 in Computer Science&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2012-1&#34;&gt;2012&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day I., Golovkin M., Palusa S., Link A., Ali G., Thomas J., &lt;strong&gt;Richardson, D.N.&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;amp; Reddy A. (2012) Interactions of SR45, an SR-like protein, with spliceosomal proteins and an intronic sequence: insights into regulated splicing. The Plant Journal 71, 936-947. &lt;em&gt;5-YR IF: 6.468, Citations: 25; Top 2% in Plant Science&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reddy, A., Rogers, M., &lt;strong&gt;Richardson, D.N.&lt;/strong&gt;, Hamilton, M. &amp;amp; Ben-Hur, A. (2012) Deciphering the plant splicing code: experimental and computational approaches for predicting alternative splicing and splicing regulatory elements. Frontiers in Plant Science 3,. &lt;em&gt;5-YR IF: 4.461, Citations: 43; Q1 in Plant Sciences&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2011&#34;&gt;2011&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Richardson, D.N.&lt;/strong&gt;, Rogers M., Labadorf A., Ben-Hur A., Guo H., Paterson A. &amp;amp; Reddy A. (2011) Comparative analysis of serine/arginine-rich proteins across 27 eukaryotes: insights into sub-family classification and extent of alternative splicing. PLoS One 6, 24542. &lt;em&gt;5-YR IF: 3.535, Citations: 31; Q1 in Agricultural and Biological Sciences (misc.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2008&#34;&gt;2008&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simmons, M., &lt;strong&gt;Richardson, D.&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;amp; Reddy, A. (2008) Incorporation of gap characters and lineage-specific regions into phylogenetic analyses of gene families from divergent clades: an example from the kinesin superfamily across eukaryotes. Cladistics 24, 372-384. &lt;em&gt;5-YR IF: 4.957, Citations: 9; Q1 in Ecology, Evolution, Behavior and Systematics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2007-1&#34;&gt;2007&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Palusa, S., Golovkin, M., Shin, S., &lt;strong&gt;Richardson, D.N.&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;amp; Reddy, A. (2007) Organ-specific, developmental, hormonal and stress regulation of expression of putative pectate lyase genes in Arabidopsis. New Phytologist 174, 537-550. &lt;em&gt;5-YR IF: 7.554, Citations: 41; Top 3% in Plant Science&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2006-2&#34;&gt;2006&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Richardson, D.N.&lt;/strong&gt;, Simmons, M. &amp;amp; Reddy, A. (2006) Comprehensive comparative analysis of kinesins in photosynthetic eukaryotes. BMC genomics 7, 18. &lt;em&gt;5-YR IF: 4.276, Citations: 89; Q1 in Biotechnology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;conference-proceedings&#34;&gt;Conference Proceedings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2009&#34;&gt;2009&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Richardson, D.N.&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;amp; Wiehe, T. (2009) Properties of Sequence Conservation in Upstream Regulatory and Protein Coding Sequences among Paralogs in Arabidopsis thaliana. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, Vol 5817, 217-228.  &lt;em&gt;Q2 in Computer Science&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;oral-communications&#34;&gt;Oral Communications&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2012-2&#34;&gt;2012&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Genome Duplication and Alternative Splicing: Gateways to Functional Diversity
&lt;em&gt;Instituto Gulbenkian de Ciência, Oeiras, Portugal, May 10, 2012&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2009-1&#34;&gt;2009&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Properties of Sequence Conservation in Upstream Regulatory and Protein Coding Sequences among Paralogs in Arabidopsis thaliana
&lt;em&gt;Seventh Annual RECOMB Satellite Workshop on Comparative Genomics, Budapest, Hungary, September 27, 2009&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2006-3&#34;&gt;2006&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comprehensive Comparative Analysis of Kinesins in Photosynthetic Eukayotes
&lt;em&gt;Collaborative Plant Biology in the Rocky Mountain/Midwest: Impacts and Future Prospects for Plant Genomics, University of Wyoming, June 1, 2006&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;poster-presentations&#34;&gt;Poster Presentations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2014-1&#34;&gt;2014&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Transcriptomic Insights into SCL30a, an Arabidopsis SR Protein Involved in Salt Stress Tolerance During Seed Germination
&lt;em&gt;Post-transcriptional Gene Regulation in Plants, June 30 - July 2, 2014, Poznan, Poland&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2008-1&#34;&gt;2008&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Promoter and Protein Divergence Independently Mediate Expression Divergence Among Arabidopsis Paralogs
&lt;em&gt;Annual Meeting of the SMBE, Barcelona, Spain, June 5-8, 2008.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2007-2&#34;&gt;2007&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Investigation of 5&amp;rsquo; Upstream Regions of Recently Duplicated Genes in Arabidopsis within a Functional Framework
&lt;em&gt;International Society for Computational Biology, Vienna, Austria, July 21-25, 2007.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crossroads in Biology
&lt;em&gt;University of Cologne, Germany, March 22, 2007.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2006-4&#34;&gt;2006&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comprehensive Comparative Analysis Of Kinesins In Photosynthetic Eukaryotes
&lt;em&gt;Plant and Animal Genome XIV, San Diego, California, January 14-18, 2006&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;languages&#34;&gt;Languages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;English&lt;/strong&gt; (Native)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Portuguese&lt;/strong&gt; (Advanced)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;German&lt;/strong&gt; (Basic)
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Markdown CV template adapted from &lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A small project example : add yours !</title>
      <link>/projects/small-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/small-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Along with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ford_Prefect_(character)&#34;&gt;Ford Prefect&lt;/a&gt;, Dent barely escapes the Earth&amp;rsquo;s destruction as it is demolished to make way for a &lt;em&gt;hyperspace bypass&lt;/em&gt;. Arthur spends the next several years, still wearing his dressing gown, helplessly launched from crisis to crisis while trying to straighten out his lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He rather enjoys tea, but seems to have trouble obtaining it in the far reaches of the galaxy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In time, he learns how to fly and carves a niche for himself as a sandwich-maker.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 20:29:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In this theme, it is possible to add sections like a Projects one for example. You can add plenty of articles about your projects and a presentation page that will be displayed before the list. All is modulable, if you don&amp;rsquo;t want something.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Hollywood-funded film version, produced and filmed in the UK, was released in April 2005, and radio adaptations of the third, fourth, and fifth novels were broadcast from 2004 to 2005. Adams did many of these adaptations, including the novels, the TV series, the computer game, and the earliest drafts of the Hollywood film’s screenplay, and some of the stage shows introduced new material written by Adams.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the home page. It will display the blog section if there is one, and a text before.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey ! Welcome to the &lt;strong&gt;Cocoa Enhanced theme&lt;/strong&gt;. Here are some articles :&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/license/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can use this page to put a license on the contents of your blog, like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MIT License (MIT)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copyright &amp;copy; 2015 Nishanth Shanmugham&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:nishanth.gerrard@gmail.com&#34;&gt;nishanth.gerrard@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy
of this software and associated documentation files (the &amp;ldquo;Software&amp;rdquo;), to deal
in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights
to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell
copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is
furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in
all copies or substantial portions of the Software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED &amp;ldquo;AS IS&amp;rdquo;, WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE
AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM,
OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN
THE SOFTWARE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>